Guide to the Time Inc. Books Group 1963-1988, 2015 MS 3009-RG 28
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Iran Publishing Project Files, 1971-1986; 3 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
  - Invoices, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3708, Folder 36-39)
  - Invoices, 1978-1979 (Offsite-box 3706, Folder 1-2)
  - Legal: Claims, 1979-1981 (Offsite-box 3706, Folder 3)
  - Legal: Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 3706, Folder 4)
  - Legal: Costs, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 3706, Folder 5)
  - Legal: Ellis, Robert, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 3706, Folder 6-7)
  - Legal: Invoice Responses, 1982 (Offsite-box 3706, Folder 8)
  - Legal: Iran-United States Claims Tribunal Court Records, 1983-1985 (Offsite-box 3706, Folder 9-15)
  - Legal: McCandless, Carolyn, 1983 (Offsite-box 3707, Folder 1)
  - Legal: Resolution, 1984 (Offsite-box 3707, Folder 2)
  - Legal: White and Case: Backup Files and Materials Collected, 1971-1982 (Offsite-box 3707, Folder 3-8)
  - Legal: White and Case: Backup Files and Materials Collected [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
  - Staff: Bagherzade, Iradj, 1977-1980 (Offsite-box 3707, Folder 9-11)
  - Staff: Marshall, Geoffrey, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3707, Folder 12)
  - Staff: Tunstell, Doug, 1977 (Offsite-box 3707, Folder 13)
  - Taxes: Calculations [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R64)
  - Taxes: Staff, 1977-1980 (Offsite-box 3707, Folder 14-17)
  - Taxes: Staff [RESTRICTED], 1977-1981 (Offsite-box R64)
- Series V. Time-Life Travel Club Records, 1969-1974; 10.25 Linear feet in 11 record cartons
  Biographical / Historical
  The Time-Life Travel Club (TLTC) started in March 1971 as a pilot program with 1000 members from the United States east coast. It was headed by Time-Life Books assistant to the publisher Ralph Gallagher as the director and Frank Farrell as the associate director. A January 1971 memorandum from Gallagher describes the TLTC as a service that would "evaluate all existing packaged travel opportunities" and deliver to members a monthly newsletter along with travel recommendations that "match their individual tastes, desires, and pocketbooks." The TLTC cited the cables sent in by Time Inc. news correspondents as prime sources for destination information.
  The TLTC registered as a travel agent with several airlines. Members on recommended trips would receive news briefings for their area. The TLTC folded around 1973.
  The Time-Life Travel Club Files document the short-lived attempt by Time-Life Books to run a travel service. Records include the proposal, finances, trip ideas, correspondence and contracts with associated vendors, and the master report summarizing the venture.
  Organized into six subseries:
  Subseries V.A. Administrative Files
  Subseries V.B. Chron File
  Subseries V.C. Exhibits
  Subseries V.D. Master Report and Supporting Files
  Subseries V.E. Promotion
  Subseries V.F. Vendors
  - Subseries V.A. Administrative Files, 1969-1972; 1.5 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    Contains all the files that were not part of another recognizable group of folders. May contain some tour operator files along with vendors of other types of products. Includes records from both director Ralph Gallagher and associate director Frank Farrell.
    - Ambassadors Club International, 1970 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 1)
    - Applicants, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 2)
    - Beneficial Management Corporation, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 3)
    - Continental Can Company, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 4)
    - Daily Data Log Sheets: February-March, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 5-6)
    - Delfold Corporation, 1970? (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 7)
    - Diners Club, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 8)
    - Dun and Bradstreet, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 9)
    - Ebersberg, Horst, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 10)
    - Employee Trips, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 11)
    - Employees, 1970 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 12)
    - Europe at Cost: Trip Solicitations, 1972 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 13)
    - Finances: Bills, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 14-15)
    - Finances: Comp List, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 16)
    - Finances: Check Requisitions, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 17-20)
    - Finances: Manufacturers Hanover, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 21)
    - Finances: Monthly Operating Statements, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 22)
    - Financials: Assumptions, 1970? (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 23)
    - Galapagos Islands Trip Test, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 24)
    - Gypsum Drywall Contractors International, 1972 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 25)
    - Incentive Travel, 1970? (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 26)
    - International Association for Medical Travelers, 1972 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 27)
    - Itineraries, 1970? (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 28)
    - Kornstein, R., 1970? (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 29)
    - Kuoni Travel Inc., 1972 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 30)
    - Legal: Galef and Jacobs, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 31-32)
    - Legal: Galef and Jacobs [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Mailings, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 33)
    - Marine Midland Bank, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 34)
    - Member: Derry, Robert, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 35)
    - National Liberty Corporation, 1970 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 36)
    - News Articles, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 37)
    - Ontario Department of Tourism, 1970 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 38)
    - Pelzman, Dick, 1971 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 39)
    - Personnel, 1970-1972 (Offsite-box 3445, Folder 40-41)
    - Personnel [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Philip L. Lowe and Associates, 1972 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 1)
    - Printing Requests, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 2)
    - Printing Travel Magazine, 1971 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 3)
    - Prospective Members Correspondence, 1971 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 4)
    - Refunds, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 5-7)
    - Sedy Palti - EAC, 1972 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 8)
    - Source of Sale Report, 1971 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 9)
    - St. John Associates, 1971 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 10)
    - Tape Programs, 1971 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 11)
    - Travel Agenda Bills, 1971 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 12)
    - Travel Agents, 1970 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 13)
    - Travel Club Law, 1971 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 14)
    - Travel Ideas, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 15)
    - Travel Guides, Brochures, etc., 1972 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 16)
    - Travel Illustrated, Inc., 1970? (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 17)
    - Travel Regulations, 1970? (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 18)
    - Trip Descriptions and Mailings, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 19-21)
    - Trip Itineraries, 1972 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 22)
  - Subseries V.B. Chron File, 1971-1974; 0.25 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    These files are called "daily copies" or "daily letters" and look like the chron files for the department and for director Ralph Gallagher. These files include letters to members with trip details.
    Organized alphabetically, then chronologically.
    - General, 1971 October-1972 June (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 23-29)
    - Gallagher, Ralph, 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 30-43)
  - Subseries V.C. Exhibits, 1969-1973; 1 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    Exhibits were in binders stored together. There was no documentation stating what they are exhibits for. Beatrice Tolleris is referred to as an editor in these records, but also held the role of the Time-Life Books director of promotion according to the Department Head Lists. "Europe at Cost: Trip Solicitations" and the master report were binders stored with these exhibit binders. While Exhibit II is missing, neither were labeled as an exhibit so it was not assumed one of them was the missing exhibit.
    Exhibits contains issues of the newsletter Word.
    Organized by exhibit number.
    - Exhibit I. General, 1969-1973 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 44)
    - Exhibit III. General, 1969-1973 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 45)
    - Exhibit IV. Comments from Members, 1972 (Offsite-box 3446, Folder 46)
    - Exhibit V. and Exhibit VI. Trip Descriptions: Mailings, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3447, Folder 1-4)
    - Exhibit VII. Bea Tolleris Correspondence with Bureaus, 1971 (Offsite-box 3447, Folder 5-6)
    - Exhibit VIII. Word Newsletter, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3447, Folder 7)
  - Subseries V.D. Master Report and Supporting Files, 1969-1974; 2.75 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
    The master report is a final report created after the travel club closed recapping its activities and reasons for ending. The report cites twenty-five supporting files, some of which have a summary at the front.
    Organized with the master report first followed by the supporting files in the order listed in the report.
    - Master Report, 1974 January (Offsite-box 3447, Folder 8)
    - Supporting Files with Summaries: American Marketing Association Finances, 1973 (Offsite-box 3447, Folder 9)
    - Supporting Files with Summaries: Anchor Savings Bank, 1972 (Offsite-box 3447, Folder 10)
    - Supporting Files with Summaries: Anchor Savings Bank [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Supporting Files with Summaries: Consultants, 1970-1972 (Offsite-box 3447, Folder 11)
    - Supporting Files with Summaries: Europe at Cost, 1971 (Offsite-box 3448, Folder 1-2)
    - Supporting Files with Summaries: Legal, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 3448, Folder 3)
    - Supporting Files with Summaries: Proposals, 1969-1973 (Offsite-box 3448, Folder 4-5)
    - Supporting Files with Summaries: Sales Reports, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3448, Folder 6)
    - Supporting Files with Summaries: Student Travel, 1972 (Offsite-box 3448, Folder 7)
    - Supporting Files with Summaries: Travel Trade Press, 1973 (Offsite-box 3448, Folder 8-11)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Ads and Tearsheets, 1972 (Offsite-box 3448, Folder 12)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: American Marketing Association, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 3448, Folder 13)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Continental Royal Services, 1973 (Offsite-box 3448, Folder 14)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Continental Royal Services [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Effort Key Cards, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3448, Folder 15)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Incentive Travel, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3449, Folder 1-5)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: International Air Transport Association (IATA) and ATC (Air traffic control?) Appointments, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 3449, Folder 6)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Mailings, 1971 (Offsite-box 3449, Folder 7)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Master List, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 3449, Folder 8-10)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Other Travel Clubs, 1970-1972 (Offsite-box 3449, Folder 11)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Profits and Losses, Planning and Budgets, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3449, Folder 12-13)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Sales, 1972 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 1)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Space Advertising, 1972 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 2)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Time-Life Travel Club Questionnaire, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 3)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Trade Press Coverage, 1972 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 4)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Travel Group Charters, 1973 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 5)
    - Supporting Files without Summaries: Travel Wholesalers, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 6)
  - Subseries V.E. Promotion, 1970-1971; 0.1 Linear feet in 4 folders
    Promotion includes the files that followed a tab labeled "Promotion." Records include correspondence, memoranda, print requests, and invoices regarding mailings sent to members, and files on the creation of the Time-Life Travel Club newsletter Word.
    - Mailings, 1971 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 7)
    - Requests, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 8)
    - Word (newsletter), 1971 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 9-10)
  - Subseries V.F. Vendors, 1970-1972; 2.25 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
    Vendors contains correspondence, contracts, and invoices from vendors the Time-Life Travel Club contracted with or bought supplies from, primarily airlines and tour operators.
    - Airlines, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 11-31)
    - Payments: A-H, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3450, Folder 32-83)
    - Payments: I-W, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3451, Folder 1-52)
    - Tour Operators: General, A-I, 1970-1972 (Offsite-box 3451, Folder 53-91)
    - Tour Operators: L-W, 1970-1972 (Offsite-box 3708, Folder 1-28)
    - Tour Operators [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)